https://www.pooleju-jitsu.com/privacy-policy/

Privacy Policy
Privacy Notice
We, meaning Poole Ju Jitsu Club, respect your privacy and
we are committed to protecting your personal data. This privacy notice informs
you about how we look after your personal data which you may have provided to
us and it tells you about your privacy rights and how the law protects you.
This notice contains the following sections, please click
on each one to navigate through the document or scroll through them. Also,
please note that the Glossary will help you to understand the meaning of some
of the terms used in this privacy notice:
It is important that you read this privacy notice. It aims
to give you information on how we collect and processes your personal data when
you use this site or make an enquiry, book a lesson or sign up as a member.
Please note, this website is not intended for children – children wishing to
train in Martial Arts will require their parents or legal guardian to contact
us.
Controller
We are the controller and responsible for your personal
data provided through this website.
We have appointed a data privacy manager who is
responsible for overseeing questions in relation to this privacy notice. If you
have any questions about this privacy notice, including any requests to
exercise your legal rights, please contact the data privacy manager using the
details set out below.
Contact details
Our details are: Poole Ju Jitsu Club,
You have the right to make a complaint at any time to the
Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO), the UK supervisory authority for data
protection issues (www.ico.org.uk). We would, however, appreciate the
opportunity to deal with your concerns before you approach the ICO so please
contact us in the first instance.
Your duty to inform us of changes
It is important that the personal data we hold about you
is accurate and current. Please keep us informed if your personal data changes
during your relationship with us.
Third-party links
This website may include links to third-party websites, plug-ins
and applications. Clicking on those links or enabling those connections may
allow third parties to collect or share data about you. We do not control these
third-party websites and are not responsible for their privacy statements. When
you leave our website, we encourage you to read the privacy notice of every
website you visit.
The data we collect about you
Personal data, or personal information, means any
information about an individual from which that person can be identified. It
does not include data where the identity has been removed (anonymous data).
We may collect, use, store and transfer different kinds of
personal data about you which we have grouped together follows:
Identity Data includes data which you
provide via our enquiry form or membership agreement, such as first name, last
name, marital status, title, date of birth and gender including such data in
respect of any child who is intended to be the student and you are the parent
or guardian.Contact Data includes email address
and telephone numbers.Training Data includes details of
attendance at tuition, and gradings/assessments undertaken,Health data.Technical Data includes [internet
protocol (IP) address, your login data, browser type and version, time zone
setting and location, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and
platform and other technology on the devices you use to access this website].Profile Data includes[your username
and password, purchases or orders made by you, your interests, preferences,
feedback and survey responses].Usage Data includes [information
about how you use our website, products and services].Marketing and Communications Data
includes [your preferences in receiving marketing from us and our third parties
and your communication preferences].Financial Data includes bank account
and payment card details.Transaction Data includes details
about payments to and from you and other details of products and services you
have purchased from us.
We also collect and use Aggregated Data such as
statistical or demographic data for any purpose. Aggregated Data may be derived
from your personal data but is not considered personal data in law as this data
does not directly or indirectly reveal your identity. However, if we combine or
connect Aggregated Data with your personal data so that it can directly or
indirectly identify you, we treat the combined data as personal data which will
be used in accordance with this privacy notice.
If you fail to provide personal data to us
Where we need personal data by law, or under the terms of
a contract we have with you and you fail to provide that data when requested,
we may not be able to perform the contract we have or are trying to enter into
with you (for example, to provide you with goods or services). In this case, we
may have to cancel a product or service you have with us but will notify you if
this is the case at the time.
How is your personal data collected
We use different methods to collect data from and about
you including through:
Direct Interactions – You may give us your data by filling
in a form or by corresponding with us by post, phone or email. This includes personal
data you provide when you:
Attend a trial lesson with us.Enquire about our products or
services.Subscribe to our publications.Request marketing to be sent to you.Give us some feedback.Enter into an agreement with us for
tuition. When you attend a lesson or grading event.Automated technologies or
interactions – As you interact with our website, we may automatically collect
Technical Data about your equipment, browsing actions and patterns. We collect
this personal data by using cookies and other similar technologies. Please see
our cookie policy for further details.Third parties – We may receive
personal data about you from various third parties as set out below:Technical Data from the following
parties including analytics providers such as Google Analytics, and advertising
networks such as Google AdWords and Facebook.Contact, Financial and Identity Data
from providers of technical, payment and delivery services such as Nest
Management Limited.Contact and Identity Data from
providers of introductory services such as Nest Management Limited (Get Into
Martial Arts).
How we use your personal data
We only use your personal data when the law allows us to.
We have set out below, in a table format, a description of
all the ways we plan to use your personal data, and which of the legal bases we
rely on to do so. We have also identified what our legitimate interests are
where appropriate:
To add details
to our database of prospective customers.
(a)
Identity
(b) Contact
(C) Student Details
(a)
Necessary for our legitimate interests (To be able to respond to your
enquiry).
Request
health data prior to training to allow us to assess suitability to receive
tuition.
(a)
Relevant conditions
(a)
Necessary for our legitimate interests.
(b) we will not store this data unless we have specific consent from you.
To add
details to and update our customer management data bases and systems.
(a)
(f) Purchases of pro-shop items
(a)
Performance of a contract with you.
(b) Necessary for our legitimate interests.
To manage
our relationship with you which will include:
(a) Notifying you about changes to our terms or privacy policy
(b) Asking you to leave a review or take a survey
(a)
Identity
(b) Contact
(c) Profile
(d) Marketing & Communications
(a)
Necessary for our legitimate interests (to keep our records updated and to study
how customers use our products/services).
To enable
you to receive offers and information, other than answers to your enquiry or
booking, providing you have opted in to that service.
(a)
(e) Marketing & Communications
(a)
Necessary for our legitimate interests (to study how customers use our
products/services, to develop them and grow our business).
To
administer and protect our business and this website (including
troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, system maintenance, support,
reporting and hosting of data)
(a)
Necessary
for our legitimate interests (to study how customers use our products/services,
to develop them, to grow our business and to inform our marketing strategy).
To use
data analytics to improve our website, products/services, marketing, customer
relationships and experiences.
(a)
Technical
(b) Usage
Necessary
for our legitimate interests (to define types of customers for our products
and services, to keep our website updated and relevant, to develop our
business and to inform our marketing strategy).
Purposes for which we will use your personal data
As described in the table above, but please note that we
may process your personal data for more than one lawful ground depending on the
specific purpose for which we are using your data. Please contact us if you
need details about the specific legal ground we are relying on to process your
personal data where more than one ground has been set out in the table above.
Marketing
We strive to provide you with choices regarding certain
personal data uses, particularly around marketing and advertising.
Promotional offers from us – marketing
We may use your personal data to form a view on what we
think you may want or need, or what may be of interest to you. This is how we
decide which products and services may be relevant for you (we call this
marketing).
You may receive marketing communications from us if you
have requested information from us or purchased services from us and, in each
case, you have opted-in to receive that marketing.
Opting out
You can ask us or third parties to stop sending you
marketing messages at any time by sending an email to us or contacting us by
phone or post. Where you opt out of receiving these marketing messages, this
will not apply to personal data provided to us as a result of a service
purchase, service experience or other transactions.
Cookies
You can set your browser to refuse all or some browser
cookies, or to alert you when websites set or access cookies. If you disable or
refuse cookies, please note that some parts of this website may become
inaccessible or not function properly. For more information about the cookies
we use, please see our cookie policy.
We use Google Analytics cookies to help understand how
visitors engage with our website. Google uses a set of cookies to collect
information and report website usage statistics without personally identifying
individual visitors to Google ourselves.
We use Google Advertising cookies to help make sure only
relevant and interested parties see our web advertisements. Google uses a set
of cookies to collect information and serve adverts over their network without
personally identifying individuals to Google ourselves.
We use Facebook to help make sure only relevant and
interested parties see our Facebook advertisements Facebook uses a set of
cookies to collect information and serve adverts over their network.
Change of purpose
We will only use your personal data for the purposes for
which we collected it, unless we reasonably consider that we need to use it for
another reason and that reason is compatible with the original purpose. If you
wish to get an explanation as to how the processing for the new purpose is
compatible with the original purpose, please contact us.
If we need to use your personal data for an unrelated
purpose, we will notify you and we will explain the legal basis which allows us
to do so.
Please note that we may process your personal data without
your knowledge or consent, in compliance with the above rules, where this is
required or permitted by law.
6. Disclosures of your personal data
We may have to share your personal
data with those set out below for the purposes set out above. External Third
Parties as set out in the Glossary.Third parties to whom we may choose
to sell, transfer, or merge parts of our business or our assets. Alternatively,
we may seek to acquire other businesses or merge with them. If a change happens
to our business, then the new owners may use your personal data in the same way
as set out in this privacy notice.
We require all third parties to respect the security of
your personal data and to treat it in accordance with the law. We do not allow
our third-party service providers to use your personal data for their own
purposes and only permit them to process your personal data for specified
purposes and in accordance with our instructions.7. International transfers
We do not transfer your personal data outside the European
Economic Area (EEA).
8. Data security
We have put in place appropriate security measures to
prevent your personal data from being accidentally lost, used or accessed in an
unauthorised way, altered or disclosed. In addition, we limit access to your
personal data to those employees, agents, contractors and other third parties
who have a business need to know. They will only process your personal data on
our instructions and they are subject to a duty of confidentiality.
We have put in place procedures to deal with any suspected
personal data breach and will notify you and any applicable regulator of a
breach where we are legally required to do so.
9. Data retention
How long will you use my personal data for?
We will only retain your personal data for as long as
necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, including for the
purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements.
To determine the appropriate retention period for personal
data, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal data, the
potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of your personal
data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can
achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal
requirements.
Details of retention periods for different aspects of your
personal data are available in our Retention Policy which you can request by contacting
us.
In some circumstances you can ask us to delete your data.
In some circumstances we may anonymise your personal data
(so that it can no longer be associated with you) for research or statistical
purposes in which case we may use this information indefinitely without further
notice to you.
10. Your legal rights
Under certain circumstances, you have rights under data
protection laws in relation to your personal data. Please see below to find out
more about these rights:
Request access to your personal data:
Request access to your personal data (commonly known as a “data subject
access request”). This enables you to receive a copy of the personal data we
hold about you and to check that we are lawfully processing it.Request correction of your personal
data:
This enables you to have any
incomplete or inaccurate data we hold about you corrected, though we may need
to verify the accuracy of the new data you provide to us.
If you become aware that We hold
incorrect information please contact us and We will make the correction, for
example: address changes and contact details changes such as address, telephone
number or e-mail details.Request erasure of your personal
data:
This enables you to ask us to delete
or remove personal data where there is no good reason for us continuing to
process it. You also have the right to ask us to delete or remove your personal
data where you have successfully exercised your right to object to processing,
where we may have processed your information unlawfully or where we are
required to erase your personal data to comply with local law. Note, however,
that we may not always be able to comply with your request of erasure for
specific legal reasons which will be notified to you, if applicable, at the
time of your request.Object to processing of your personal
data:
Where we are relying on a legitimate
interest (or those of a third party) and there is something about your
particular situation which makes you want to object to processing on this
ground as you feel it impacts on your fundamental rights and freedoms. You also
have the right to object where we are processing your personal data for direct
marketing purposes. In some cases, we may demonstrate that we have compelling
legitimate grounds to process your information which override your rights and
freedoms.Request restriction of processing
your personal data:
Request restriction of processing of
your personal data. This enables you to ask us to suspend the processing of
your personal data in the following scenarios: (a) if you want us to establish
the data’s accuracy; (b) where our use of the data is unlawful but you do not
want us to erase it; (c) where you need us to hold the data even if we no
longer require it as you need it to establish, exercise or defend legal claims;
or (d) you have objected to our use of your data but we need to verify whether
we have overriding legitimate grounds to use it.Request transfer of your personal
data:
Request the transfer of your personal
data to you or to a third party. We will provide to you, or a third party you
have chosen, your personal data in a structured, commonly used,
machine-readable format. Note that this right only applies to automated
information which you initially provided consent for us to use or where we used
the information to perform a contract with you.
Right to withdraw consent:
Withdraw consent at any time where we are relying on
consent to process your personal data. However, this will not affect the
lawfulness of any processing carried out before you withdraw your consent. If
you withdraw your consent, we may not be able to provide certain products or
services to you. We will advise you if this is the case at the time you
withdraw your consent.
If you wish to exercise any of the rights set out above,
please contact us.
No fee usually required
You will not have to pay a fee to access your personal
data (or to exercise any of the other rights). However, we may charge a
reasonable fee if your request is clearly unfounded, repetitive or excessive.
Alternatively, we may refuse to comply with your request in these
circumstances.
What we may need from you
We may need to request specific information from you to
help us confirm your identity and ensure your right to access your personal
data (or to exercise any of your other rights). This is a security measure to
ensure that personal data is not disclosed to any person who has no right to
receive it. We may also contact you to ask you for further information in
relation to your request to speed up our response.
Time limit to respond
We try to respond to all legitimate requests within one
month. Occasionally it may take us longer than a month if your request is
particularly complex or you have made a number of requests. In this case, we
will notify you and keep you updated.
11. Glossary
We, us, our means owners of this website and the business
providing tuition and other services which you may be using or enquiring about
through this site.
Legitimate Interest means the interest of our business in
conducting and managing our business to enable us to give you the best
service/product and the best and most secure experience. We make sure we
consider and balance any potential impact on you (both positive and negative)
and your rights before we process your personal data for our legitimate
interests. We do not use your personal data for activities where our interests
are overridden by the impact on you (unless we have your consent or are
otherwise required or permitted to by law). You can obtain further information
about how we assess our legitimate interests against any potential impact on
you in respect of specific activities by contacting us.
Performance of Contract means processing your data where
it is necessary for the performance of a contract to which you are a party or
to take steps at your request before entering into such a contract.
Comply with a legal or regulatory obligation means
processing your personal data where it is necessary for compliance with a legal
or regulatory obligation that we are subject to.
External Third Parties means:
National governing bodies, regulatory associations and
similar organisations relating to the tuition subject acting as processors or
joint controllers.
Any franchisor acting as processor or joint controller who
has granted us a franchise to carry on our business.
Service providers acting as processors who provide IT and
system administration services including but not limited to Poole Ju-jitsu
club.
Professional advisers acting as processors or joint
controllers including lawyers, bankers, auditors and insurers who provide
consultancy, banking, legal, insurance and accounting services.
HM Revenue & Customs, regulators and other authorities
acting as processors or joint controllers who require reporting of processing
activities in certain circumstances.
Any changes we may make to our privacy policy in the
future will be posted on this page and, where appropriate, notified to you by
e-mail. However, we advise that you check this page regularly to keep up to
date with any necessary changes.
Search for:
Disability in Martial Arts
Recent Commentsandy Walker on Jackie’s Training DiaryJackie on Jackie’s Training DiaryAndy Walker on Adam’s Training DiaryHarvey on Harvey’s Training DiaryHarvey on Harvey’s Training DiaryAdam on Adam’s Training DiaryAndy Walker on Haiden’s Training DiaryBecca on Haiden’s Training DiaryBecca on Adam’s Training DiaryBecca on Jackie’s Training DiaryArchives
April 2020
March 2020
January 2020
December 2019
November 2019
October 2019
Follow UsInstagramTwitterFacebook
Poole Bushido Ju-jitsu Copyright 2020 Proudly powered by WordPress
|
Theme: NewsMagbd by eDataStyle.
Search for:
